<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no" ?>
<modDesc descVersion="107">
	<author>Schluppe</author>
	<version>1.0.1.0</version>
	
	<title>
		<en>Courseplay GPS Extension</en>
		<de>Courseplay GPS Erweiterung</de>
		<fr>Extension GPS Courseplay</fr>
	</title>
	
	<description>
	<en><![CDATA[Courseplay GPS Extension
Description: This mod adds automatic steering to Vehicles based on Courseplay courses.
In order to use this mod there is the need to have Courseplay installed.

Afterwards you can use Field courses to enable GPS tracking when driving tractors or harvesters. 
The motivation was to have the chance to smoothly swap between the CP helper and manual driving, but still using GPS tracking. 
The Giants automatic steering does come with own courses might causing an offset or different tracks than CoursePlay uses. 
In general does the CP course generator offer much more options to control the details of courses incl. the option to load and save them. 
An example is cutting the grass (10m working width) and afterwards picking it up by simply loading the same course.


How to use this mod:
- Assign an activation key in the settings
- Generate or load a CP course
- As from this moment the you can activate the automatic steering when driving onto a field
- The system picks the closest way points and start to steer automatically

Features:
- Automatically follows the CP course
- The system is foreseen for working on fields only.

Parameters to control the following features:
- GPS tracking disabled (end of the row, end of the course, on connecting path or never)
- Disable cruise control (end of the row, end of the course, on connecting path or never)
- Remove Giants automatic steering courses when a CP course is loaded
- Define the mode to show the path of the course
- Time to hide the path after activating the automatic steering

Changelog 1.0.0.0:
- Initial creation

Changelog 1.0.1.0:
- Fixed an issue when running FS25 in French
]]></en>
	<de><![CDATA[Courseplay GPS Erweiterung
Beschreibung: Diese Mod fügt die Spurführung auf Basis von Courseplay Kursen hinzu.
Um diese Mod zu verwenden, muss Courseplay installiert sein.

Anschließend können Sie Feldkurse nutzen, um die GPS-Spurführung beim Fahren von Traktoren oder Erntemaschinen zu aktivieren.
Die Motivation war, einen nahtlosen Wechsel zwischen CP-Helfern und manuellem Fahren zu ermöglichen und dabei die GPS-Spurführung beizubehalten.
Die automatische Spurführung von Giants verwendet eigene Kurse, die zu ggf. Abweichungen zu den Courseplay Kursen hat.
Weiterhin bietet der CP-Kursgenerator deutlich mehr Optionen zur Steuerung der Kursdetails, einschließlich der Möglichkeit, Kurse zu laden und zu speichern.
Ein Beispiel ist das Mähen von Gras (z.B. 10m Arbeitsbreite) und das anschließend Aufladen, indem Sie einfach denselben Kurs laden.

So verwenden Sie diese Mod:
- Weisen Sie in den Einstellungen einen Tastenkombination zur Aktivierung zu.
- Generieren oder laden Sie einen CP-Kurs.
- Ab diesem Zeitpunkt können Sie die automatische Lenkung aktivieren.
- Das System wählt die nächstgelegenen Wegpunkte und beginnt automatisch zu lenken.

Funktionen:
- Folgt automatisch dem CP-Kurs.
- Das System ist nur für die Verwendung auf Feldern vorgesehen.

Parameter zur Steuerung der folgenden Funktionen:
- GPS-Tracking deaktivieren (am Ende der Reihe, am Ende des Kurs, auf dem Verbindungsweg oder nie).
- Tempomat deaktivieren (am Ende der Reihe, am Ende des Kurs, auf dem Verbindungsweg oder nie).
- Entfernt die automatische Spurführung von Giants, sobald eine CP-Strecke geladen ist (damit kann die gleiche Tastenbelegung verwendet werden).
- Parameter der festlegt, in welchem ​​Modus die Streckenführung angezeigt werden soll.
- Parameter der festlegt, wann die Streckenführung nach Aktivierung der automatischen Lenkung ausgeblendet werden soll.

Changelog 1.0.0.0:
- Initiale Erstellung.

Changelog 1.0.1.0:
- Ein Problem beim Ausführen von FS25 auf Französisch wurde behoben.
]]></de>
<fr><![CDATA[Extension GPS Courseplay
Description : Ce mod ajoute la direction automatique aux véhicules grâce aux parcours générés par Courseplay.

Pour utiliser ce mod, Courseplay doit être installé.
Vous pouvez ensuite utiliser les parcours de terrain pour activer le suivi GPS lors de la conduite de tracteurs ou de moissonneuses-batteuses.
L'objectif était de permettre une transition fluide entre l'assistance Courseplay et la conduite manuelle, tout en conservant le suivi GPS.
La direction automatique de Giants utilise ses propres parcours, ce qui peut entraîner un décalage ou des trajectoires différentes de celles utilisées par Courseplay.
De manière générale, le générateur de parcours de Courseplay offre beaucoup plus d'options pour contrôler les détails des parcours, notamment la possibilité de les charger et de les enregistrer.
Par exemple, pour tondre l'herbe (largeur de travail de 10 m) et la ramasser ensuite, il suffit de charger le même parcours.

Comment utiliser ce mod :
- Attribuez une touche d'activation dans les paramètres.
- Générez ou chargez un parcours CP.
- À partir de ce moment, vous pouvez activer le pilotage automatique lorsque vous entrez dans un champ.
- Le système sélectionne les points de passage les plus proches et commence à piloter automatiquement.

Fonctionnalités :
- Suivi automatique du parcours CP.
- Le système est conçu pour fonctionner uniquement sur les champs.

Paramètres pour contrôler les fonctionnalités suivantes :
- Suivi GPS désactivé (fin de rangée, fin de parcours, sur la voie de liaison ou jamais).
- Désactivation du régulateur de vitesse (fin de rangée, fin de parcours, sur la voie de liaison ou jamais).
- Suppression des parcours de pilotage automatique Giants lorsqu'un parcours CP est chargé.
- Définition du mode d'affichage du parcours.
- Délai de masquage du parcours après l'activation du pilotage automatique.


Changelog 1.0.0.0:
- Configuration initiale.

Changelog 1.0.1.0:
- Correction d'un problème d'exécution de FS25 en français.
]]></fr>
	</description>
	
	<iconFilename>icon_CourseplayGps.dds</iconFilename>
	<multiplayer supported="true"/>
	
	<extraSourceFiles>
		<sourceFile filename="RegisterSpecialization.lua" />
	</extraSourceFiles>	

	<dependencies>				
		<dependency>FS25_Courseplay</dependency>
    </dependencies>

	<l10n>
		<text name="input_FS25_CourseplayGpsExtension_GPS_ONOFF">
			<de>Courseplay GPS ein/aus</de>
			<en>Courseplay GPS on/off</en>
		</text>
		<text name="GPS_OFF">
			<de>GPS aus</de>
			<en>GPS off</en>
		</text>
		<text name="GPS_ON">
			<de>GPS ein</de>
			<en>GPS on</en>
		</text>
		<text name="ShowCourse_Deactivated">
			<de>Ausgeblendet</de>
			<en>Hidden</en>
		</text>
		<text name="ShowCourse_StartStop">
			<de>Nur Start/Ende</de>
			<en>Start/stop only</en>
		</text>
		<text name="ShowCourse_CurrentWaypoint">
			<de>Aktuelle Wegpunkte</de>
			<en>Current waypoints</en>
		</text>
		<text name="ShowCourse_All">
			<de>Alle Wegpunkte</de>
			<en>All waypoints</en>
		</text>
		<text name="ShowCourse_Unchanged">
			<de>Unverändert</de>
			<en>Unchanged</en>
		</text>
		<text name="WpTrigger_Never">
			<de>Niemals</de>
			<en>Never</en>
		</text>		
		<text name="WpTrigger_EndOfRow">
			<de>Ende der Reihe</de>
			<en>End of row</en>
		</text>		
		<text name="WpTrigger_OnConnectionPoints">
			<de>An Verbindungspunkten</de>
			<en>On connecting path</en>
		</text>		
		<text name="WpTrigger_EndOfCourse">
			<de>Am Ende</de>
			<en>End of course</en>
		</text>		
		<text name="DisableGiantsAiSteering_warning">
			<de>Kurs aus der Giants Spurführung gelöscht, da ein Kurs in Courseplay GPS aktiv ist</de>
			<en>Course of GPS tracking removed due to active course in Courseplay GPS.</en>
		</text>
		<text name="FS25_CourseplayGps_GPS_TRACKING">
			<de>GPS Spurführung</de>
			<en>GPS Tracking</en>
		</text>
		<text name="FS25_CourseplayGps_Vehicle_setting_cpGpsDisableCruiseControl_title">
			<de>Abschaltung Tempomat</de>
			<en>Disable cruise control</en>
		</text>
		<text name="FS25_CourseplayGps_Vehicle_setting_cpGpsDisableCruiseControl_tooltip">
			<de>Mit diesem Wert wird definiert, wann der Tempomat abgeschaltet wird.</de>
			<en>Defines the moment of disabling the cruise control.</en>
		</text>
		<text name="FS25_CourseplayGps_Vehicle_setting_cpGpsHidePathTime_title">
			<de>Zeit zum Ausblenden der CP Punkte beim Aktivieren</de>
			<en>Time to hide the path after activation</en>
		</text>
		<text name="FS25_CourseplayGps_Vehicle_setting_cpGpsHidePathTime_tooltip">
			<de>Gibt die Zeit in Sekunden an, nachdem die Punkte vom Kurs ausgeblendet werden, wenn die Spurführung aktiviert wird. Bei 0 ist das Ausblenden deaktiviert.</de>
			<en>Defines the time in seconds after which the way points from the course are hidden when GPS tracking is enabled. A value of 0 disables hiding the path.</en>
		</text>
		<text name="FS25_CourseplayGps_Vehicle_setting_cpGpsPathDisplay_title">
			<de>Kurs anzeigen</de>
			<en>Show course</en>
		</text>
		<text name="FS25_CourseplayGps_Vehicle_setting_cpGpsPathDisplay_tooltip">
			<de>Zeigt den Kurs des aktuell gewählten Fahrzeugs</de>
			<en>Show the current course of the vehicle.</en>
		</text>
		<text name="FS25_CourseplayGps_Vehicle_setting_cpGpsDisableGiantsAiSteering_title">
			<de>Leeren der Giants Spurführung</de>
			<en>Clearing the course of Giants auto-steering</en>
		</text>
		<text name="FS25_CourseplayGps_Vehicle_setting_cpGpsDisableGiantsAiSteering_tooltip">
			<de>Sobald ein Kurs in CP geladen ist, dann wird der Kurs in der Giants-Spurführung geleert. Das hat den Vorteil, dass man die Aktivierung auf die gleichen Tasten legen kann und somit immer gleich die Spurführung ein-/ausschalten kann. Wenn beide Funktionen geladene Kurse haben gewinnt sonst einer. Wenn die Aktivierung unterschiedliche Tastenbelegungen haben, kann die Funktion absgeschaltet bleiben.</de>
			<en>As soon as a course is loaded into CP, the course of the Giants' guidance system is cleared. This has the advantage that you can assign same key-bindung to the activation, allowing you to always turn the guidance on and off with the same key. If both functions have a loaded courses, one wins. If the activations have different key assignments, the function can remain disabled.</en>
		</text>
		<text name="FS25_CourseplayGps_Vehicle_setting_cpGpsDisableSteering_title">
			<de>Abschaltung der Spurführung</de>
			<en>Disable GPS tracking</en>
		</text>
		<text name="FS25_CourseplayGps_Vehicle_setting_cpGpsDisableSteering_tooltip">
			<de>Mit diesem Wert wird definiert, wann die Spurführung abgeschaltet wird.</de>
			<en>Defines the moment of disabling the GPS tracking.</en>
		</text>
	</l10n>

	<inputBinding>
		<actionBinding action="FS25_CourseplayGpsExtension_GPS_ONOFF">
			<binding device="KB_MOUSE_DEFAULT" input="KEY_lctrl KEY_lshift KEY_g" axisComponent="+" neutralInput="0" index="1"/>
		</actionBinding>
	</inputBinding>

	<actions>
		<action name="FS25_CourseplayGpsExtension_GPS_ONOFF" category="VEHICLE"/>
	</actions>
	
	<registerSpecializations>
		<registerSpecialization name="CourseplayGpsExtension" className="CourseplayGpsExtension" filename="CourseplayGpsExtension.lua" searchedSpecializations="drivable"/>
	</registerSpecializations>
</modDesc>